When science lost its innocence.
Adventures of a Mathematician is a drama, history
film directed by Thorsten Klein.
The warmhearted story of Polish immigrant and
mathematician Stan Ulam, who moved to the U.S.
in the 1930s.
Stan deals with the difficult losses of family and friends all while
helping to create the hydrogen bomb and the first computer.
Stan Ulam, played by Philippe Tłokiński.
Francoise, played by Esther Garrel.
Jack Calkin, played by Sam Keeley.
Edward Teller, played by Joel Basman.
John von Neumann, played by Fabian Kocięcki.
Robert Oppenheimer, played by Ryan Gage.
Alice's Adventures in Wonderland (also known as  Alice in Wonderland) is an 1865 English
children's novel by Lewis Carroll, a mathematics don at the University of Oxford.
It details the story of a girl named Alice who falls through a rabbit
hole into a fantasy world of anthropomorphic creatures.
It is seen as an example of the literary nonsense genre.
The artist John Tenniel provided 42 wood-engraved illustrations for the book.
The novel received positive reviews upon release and is now one of the best-known works of Victorian literature; its narrative,
structure, characters and imagery have had a wide influence on popular culture and literature, especially in the fantasy genre.
It is credited as helping end an era of didacticism in children's literature,
inaugurating an era in which writing for children aimed to "delight or entertain".
The tale plays with logic, giving the story lasting
popularity with adults as well as with children.
The titular character Alice shares her name with Alice Liddell, a girl Carroll knew;
scholars disagree about the extent to which the character was based upon her.
The novel has never been out of print and has
been translated into 174 languages.
Its legacy includes adaptations to screen, radio, visual art, ballet, opera, and
musical theatre, as well as theme parks, board games and video games.
Carroll published a sequel in 1871 entitled Through the Looking-Glass and a
shortened version for young children, The Nursery "Alice", in 1890.
The tone is emotional.